ALENA MELO

+ 353 834145174 | alenamelo@yahoo.com.br | Dublin, Ireland LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/alenamelo | EU Citizen

Professional Summary

Communicative, proactive and bilingual professional (Portuguese and English) with over 7 years experience in administration duties, customer service and copy writing. Post-graduation degree in Business Communication. Excellent attention to details, strong organizational, IT and written skills. Ability to prioritise key tasks, manage multiple tasks simultaneously and meet deadlines. I am willing to learn and currently looking for an administrative role to develop my career even further.

Education

- Post Graduate Degree in Business Communication | AVM College Rio de Janeiro, Brazil
 | 02/2013 02/2014
- Bachelor Degree in Advertising | Estácio de Sá College Rio de Janeiro, Brazil | 03/2002 03/2008

Further Education

- General English Course Advanced | Berlitz / IBAT Dublin, Ireland | 12/2018 12/2020
- Storytelling | FAETEC Rio de Janeiro, Brazil | 07/2013 11/2013
- Audiovisual Production | Cinema Nosso Rio de Janeiro, Brazil | 01/2015 05/2015

Professional Experience

Receptionist NIBRT | Dublin, Ireland

08/2022 - Present

- Provide front of house and reception services for the client directly.
- Handle the client's reception duties with care, commitment and always in a courteous manner.
- Manage and respond to requirements and requests to ensure a high level of customer support to clients.
- Manage visitor access cards and signing in process.
- Distribute calls throughout the building, take messages if necessary and e-mail relevant individuals without delay.
- Check e-mails and react accordingly.
- Maintain accurate and efficient management information systems.
- Ensure all activities are carried out and in accordance with H&S policies.
- Assist with retail shop at reception area.

English Customer Support Analyst Telus International | Dublin, Ireland

03/2022 - 08/2022

- Responsible for providing support to customers by investigating, troubleshooting and resolving cases across multiple channels.
- Communicate effectively and efficiently with all users who are seeking your help or advice, thinking critically in order to solve user issues via email.
- Investigate and research user issues and identify and escalate bugs so they can be resolved as quickly as possible.
- Troubleshoot, negotiate and provide information and solutions to customers.

General Assistant 08/2021 - 03/2022

Aramark | Dublin, Ireland

- Responsible for managing, purchasing, distribution and inventory of the material stock.
- Responsible for internal appearance and upkeep.
- Highlighting any items or areas that need maintenance.

Sales Assistant (Christmas temporary contract) Penneys | Dublin, Ireland

11/2020 - 01/2021

- Deal with a large number of customers daily.
- Deliver excellent sales and customer service.
- Update sales reconciliation report and cash-up.
- Organise displays and windows and coordinated dressing rooms.

General Operative Cagney Cleaning | Dublin, Ireland

04/2019 - 12/2020

Responsible for all aspects of daily cleaning duties including training of new staff.

Copywriter/Copy editor 3A Worldwide | Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

11/2013 - 11/2018

- Develop concepts, titles and texts for advertising campaigns, ensuring clarity, conciseness, cohesion, coherence and harmony to texts.
- Responsible for proofreading and checking spelling, syntax, precision, standardisation and conventions of all the texts before being published.
- Annual communication planning for clients, such as GSK (GlaxoSmithKline).
- Text Translation (English Portuguese).

Administrative Assistant SMASDH-RJ | Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Social Assistance and Human Rights Office – Public Sector)

02/2011 - 01/2013

- Journalistic coverage, such as article writing, production and coordinated the editing of photos and videos.
- Production of all the material for internal communication.
- Responsible for the customer record in excel (CRM).
- Assisted with the coordination of internal and external events.
- Responsible for administrative tasks in the department such as scheduling meetings; managing the shared email inbox, writing correspondence memos and letters.
- Managed and inventory control of material stock.
- Sending an employee's productivity report to the responsible agency.

Teacher/Events Assistant School of Dance and Arts | Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

03/2009 - 05/2012

- Teach oriental dance, create choreographies and rehearse with the students for the dance events.
- Assist in the production, coordination and presentation of the school's events.

Communication Assistant (Internship) Kelimaski | Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

- Capture support and sponsorship for projects.
- Assist in the organisation, promotion and production of events.
- Create and distribute promotional material.
- Welcome the public and give instructions to musicians and dancers.
- Produce content and update the school's website.

Receptionist FINEP | Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (Funding for Research Projects)

04/2006 - 10/2006

- First point of contact of the company's visitors, managing the communication in person, by phone calls and emails.
- Manage the company-wide correspondence.

Volunteer Experience

Customer Service/ Sales Assistant Vincent's Shop | Dublin, Ireland

01/2019 - 08/2019

- Deliver sales and customer service.
- Update sales reconciliation report and cash-up.
- Organise displays and windows.

Skills

- Interpersonal, verbal and written communication
- Attention to detail
- Organisational skills
- Ability to work on my own initiative and as part of a team
- Flexibility and proactivity
- Ability to prioritise tasks
- Problem solving
- MS Office 365 (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, Teams, OneDrive)
- Slack
- Customer Support
- Account Management
- Quality Assurance
- Proofreading and text editing
- Translation
- Communication planning
- Customer Relationship Management (CRM)
- Business Process Outsourcing (BPO)
- KYC Verification
- AML

References

References available upon request.